Kevin Mbui Software Developer

<u>kevinmushan@gmail.com</u> • +(254) 791-560-183 github.com/kevinmbuicode/ • linkedin.com/in/kevinmbui/ • mushan.tech

Summary Statement

I'm a Software developer with 2+ years of experience. I have increased code delivery speed by 29%, enhanced site speed by 76%, and boosted site relevance with SEO by 68% in 6 months while regularly training novices. I am seeking to leverage proven leadership and expertise to become the next senior software engineer.

I am majored in MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js, and have fundamental knowledge of IBM Cloud, Microservices, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Docker, Python, Django and Git.

Work Experience

Frontend Software Developer, Hybrid Marketing Group

Hybrid Marketing Group, Nairobi, KE

May 2020 – June 2022

- I worked with a team on various tasks, including Design, Development, and Marketing.
- I oversaw the redesign of a website, added heatmaps and boosted SEO leading to 75% sales increase.
- I developed, tested, reviewed, and delivered websites with 100% on-time record and according to service level objectives.
- I integrated various payments methods such as Stripe, PayPal, and Mpesa.

Property Manager, John's Apartments

John's Apartments, Nairobi, KE

July 2020 – Present

- I collect and manage rent, solve internal conflicts, identify areas affecting the tenants and solving any found issues.
- I Initiate projects that upgrade the apartments, and maintaining the apartments.
- I establish trust and understanding in everybody for a comfortable home environment for everyone.
- I seek feedback from tenants about how new implementations may or have affected them.

Education

Computer Software Engineering

Zetech University, Nairobi, KE *May 2018 – July 2020*

• Relevant Coursework: Artificial Intelligence, Java, C++, PHP, Mobile Programming, Discrete Mathematics, Calculus 1 & 2, Database Management System, Computer Ethics.

Technical Skills

Advanced (★★★★★): HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6, React, Git, Architectural Patterns (MVC), Node.js, Agile Methodologies (Scrum), MongoDB, Express.js, Firebase, SEO.

Familiar (★★★★☆): IBM Cloud, Python, Django, OpenShift, Microservices, Kubernetes, Docker.

Soft Skills

 Relevant soft skills: Communication, Problem-solving, Collaboration, Self-motivated, Empathy, Creative Thinking, Time management

Certifications

- Full Stack Cloud Developer (Coursera/IBM), January 2022
- Cloud Application Development Foundations (Coursera/IBM), January 2022

Honors & Awards

Full Stack Cloud Development Capstone Project (Coursera), January 2022

Projects (Business & Technical)

Full Stack Cloud Development Capstone Project

A web app to access a central database for all dealerships in USA, conditionally allow only logged in users to leave reviews, any user to view sorted reviews by state and branch. Use IBM NLU to determine the sentiment of the review, containerize and deploy to Kubernetes.

- Technology used: Django, Kubernetes, IBM cloud, Html, CSS, IBM Cloudant.
- Link: https://github.com/kevinmbuicode/Cloud_App_Development_Capstone

Modern Ecommerce with Stripe Checkout

A beautiful modern ecommerce website. Integrated with Stripe payments. Accomplished using routes, API calls, and a great User Interface (UI), and User Experience (UX). Still in development.

- Technology used: React, Stripe, Commerce.js.
- Link: https://www.mushan.tech/

Cryptocurrency Watch

A web app to list the top 100 currencies in the market. The goal was to create awareness of cryptocurrencies and show case the top winners and losers of the day easily. And a chart to show the trend of a selected coin in the past 24 hours, 30 days, 3 months and 1 year.

- Technology used: React, Material UI, Chart.js, Vercel.
- Link: https://www.mushan.tech/

Volunteer Work

• Assist fellows fix bugs.

Courses outside school

- IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer, (Coursera)
- The Odin Project
- Frontend Masters